Nicole: So, let’s look at some of the
key organisations that are involved
in cyber security in the UK today.
Let’s first look at the National Cyber
Security Centre also known as the NCSC.
The NCSC is an organisation launched
by the government in 2016, set up to
support the most critical organisations
in the public sector as well as
industry and the general public.
Their aim is to 'help make the UK the
safest place to live and work online'.
They offer practical guidance and
will respond to any cyber security
incidents they are made aware of, to
minimise the harm that they may cause.
They also work collaboratively with law
enforcement, defence and intelligence and
security services and overseas partners.
Their website is a source of
information for individuals and
families to large organisations,
including the self-employed, small,
and medium businesses, the public
sector, and cyber professionals.
The information they give can range from
advice about what to do with spyware,
like a scam message about a fake parcel
delivery, to how to defend organisations
against malware and ransomware attacks.
They also have a wealth of information
on all different aspects of cyber
security and resources and opportunities
for schools and students who are
interested in cyber security.
For more information and guidance their
website is well worth checking out.
Next let’s look at Government
Communications Headquarters
also known as GCHQ
GCHQ are the UK's intelligence,
security, and cyber agency and their
'mission is to keep the country
safe in the real world and online'.
They work with the secret intelligence
agencies, police, and the private sector
and with overseas partners to do this.
They have always been at the
heart of the British intelligence
and security agencies.
The NCSC is part of GCHQ and
together they aim to protect the
UK citizens and business from
global attack, that may impact the
country's security and prosperity.
For more information on GCHQ
check out their website.
The Information Commissioners Office
or ICO is the UK's independent body
set up to uphold information rights.
It works in the public interest and
promotes openness by public bodies
and data privacy for individuals.
It shows clear guidelines about
individuals rights regarding
their data and its use and the
individual’s right to access their
data or correct it if necessary.
For more information on the
ICO check out their website.
And finally let’s look at the UK
Cyber Security Council who state that
“The UK Cyber Security Council is
the self-regulatory body, and voice,
for UK cyber security education,
training and skills, with a mandate
from the UK government to be the focal
point through which industry and the
professional landscape advise, shape
and inform national policy on cyber
security professional standards”.
They support the UK Governments National
Cyber Security Strategy to make the UK
a safe place to live and work online.
They are an umbrella body for
the cyber security profession
and aim to be a reference point
for cyber security professionals.
For more information on them
check out their website.